Finding Aid for the Lady Agnes Anne Adams Papers LSC.1361
UCLA Library Special Collections
Lady Agnes Anne Adams papers
1914-1954
UCLA Library Special Collections
Adams, Lady (Agnes Anne)
LSC.1361
1 unknown (1 oversize box)
Lady Adams (1869-1942) was born Agnes Anne Cook in Scotland. She wrote popular articles for newspapers and magazines. The collection consists of manuscripts, correspondence, photographs, and ephemera related to Lady Adams's life and writings.
4 boxes (2.0 linear ft.)
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Maven Thorpe, 1979.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 994621403606533
We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form located on our website: Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special Collections.
Biography
Lady Adams was born Agnes Anne Cook in Scotland in 1869; married John Adams in Glasgow, 1893; his academic career took him to the University of London, University of California at Berkeley, and UCLA and also on travels to New Zealand, Australia, and South Africa; Lady Adams wrote popular articles for newspapers and magazines; widowed, 1934; died in Los Angeles, 1942; posthumous selection and bibliography of writings published as Tea-Time (1942).
Scope and Content
Collection consists of manuscripts, correspondence, photographs, and ephemera related to the life and writings of Lady Adams. Includes material concerning her friend, Maven Thorpe.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Manuscripts (Boxes 1-2).
Notes, fragments, clippings, speeches, photographs, ephemera (Box 3).
Correspondence (Box 4).
Posters and watercolor of New Zealand (Box 5).
Women journalists -- Archives.; Adams, Lady (Agnes Anne), 1869-1942--Archives.; Thorpe, Maven.
- Manuscripts by Lady Adams (Box 1, Box 2)
  General note
  Note: Titles of manuscripts are in alphabetical order.
  - Adventures Round Rattlesnakes. Los Angeles, undated; 5 leaves with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    With 1 leaf (2pp.) of notes.
  - Ah, Promise. Los Angeles, undated; 5 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    With 1 leaf holograph notes.
  - Aktin. Los Angeles, undated; 2 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Aliens Must Register. Los Angeles, undated; 5 leaves. Typescript with holograph notes. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    With 5 variant copies.
  - Ambiguous to Foreigners. Los Angeles, undated; 2 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    With 1 variant copy.
  - The American Dollar, Through an Englishwoman's Eyes. Los Angeles, undated; 23 leaves with additional pages laid in. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    With 4 clippings.
  - Animals' Cemetery. Cambridge, Massachusetts, undated; 2 leaves. With 1 clipping. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Are We a Reticent Nation? n.p., undated; 3 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. Pages are numbered 49, 51, 52. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Art of Table Conversation. n.p., undated; 26 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. Sewn with cotton cord in upper left corner. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - At Tea Time in the Nursery. Los Angeles, undated; 2 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Beethoven, Schubert, and Sullivan. Los Angeles, undated; 23 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Black Edward. Los Angeles, undated; 4 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    With 1 variant copy, letter of rejection from the Cape Times, and a leaf of holograph notes.
  - Black Edward on Religion and the Movies. n.p., undated; 4 leaves. Typescript with corrections. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bogeys. Los Angeles, undated; 3 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Boys and Books in Los Angeles. Los Angeles, undated; 5 leaves. With 2pp. inserted. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - A Car in a Restaurant. Los Angeles, undated; 5 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - The Case for Day-Dreaming. Los Angeles, undated; 13 leaves. Typescript with manuscript corrections. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Sir John Adams's name and address are on the title page.
  - Change. Los Angeles, undated; 2 leaves. Typescript. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - The Co-ed's Ideal Man. Los Angeles, undated; 3 leaves. Typescript with holograph notes. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    With a variant copy (4 leaves) and 2 leaves of holograph notes.
  - The Collecting Germ. Los Angeles, 1935.; 6 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    With a variant copy and 2 leaves of holograph notes.
  - Comforts for Kit. Los Angeles, undated; 9 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - The Cop and the Bobby. Los Angeles, undated; 3 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    With rejection slip from an editor attached.
  - Cues at the Pot Boilers. Los Angeles, January 1926.; 2 leaves. Typescript. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    With letter of transmittal from Mrs. Fred Stoddard, Glendale, to Mrs. J.M. Slemons, Los Angeles, July 26, 1942.
  - Delta Kappa Gamma Interests. Los Angeles, undated; 4 leaves. Typescript. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Dickens--Boston. 1842-1926. Los Angeles, undated; 3 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    With another typescript copy.
  - The Differences Are... n.p., undated; 5 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - The Donkey's Well. Adapted from the German of Rudolph Baumbach. Los Angeles, undated; 5 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Drooling. Los Angeles, undated; 4 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - The Eclipse of the Lecturer. n.p., 1930.; 4 leaves. Typescript. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    With a carbon copy. Published in the London Times, February 23, 1930.
  - Editors and Business Men. Los Angeles, undated; 3 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Embalming in America. Los Angeles, undated; 3 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Eternal Feminine in California. Los Angeles, undated; 2 leaves. (Box 1, Folder 32)
    With 1 letter of regrets from the Sunday London Times, and 2 leaves of holograph notes.
  - Every Day Drama in Los Angeles. Los Angeles, undated; 4 leaves. Typescript. With 1 variant copy. (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Both are incomplete.
  - Expensive Education. Los Angeles, undated; 9 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 34)
    With 1 variant copy, 3 leaves of holograph notes, and 1 card from the Herald.
  - The Farmers' Market. Los Angeles, undated; 2 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Father and Son. Los Angeles, undated; 2 leaves. Typescript. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Feminine Interests in the Dominions. n.p., undated; 22 numbered leaves with additional pages laid in. Sewn with cotton cord in upper left corner. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - The First Christmas Cards. Los Angeles, undated; 2 leaves. With holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 38)
    With 3 clippings and 1 leaf of holograph notes.
  - Foot and Mouth Disease in California. Los Angeles, undated; 8 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 39)
    With 1 variant copy and 1 leaf of holograph notes.
  - Foyles' for Books. Los Angeles, undated; 4 leaves. Typescript with holograph notes. (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Free Lance Work in England. n.p., undated; 26 numbered leaves with additional pages laid in. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 41)
    With clipping and 1 leaf holograph notes.
  - The Freight of the Mayflower. n.p., 1923.; 13 numbered leaves with additional pages laid in. Typescript. (Box 1, Folder 42)
    With author's note that this was read at the 303rd celebration of the signing of the Mayflower compact, Century Club Building, San Francisco.
  - The Future Farmers of America. Los Angeles, undated; 9 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Going Down. n.p., 1929; 2 leaves. Typescript. (Box 1, Folder 44)
    With a carbon copy. Published in the Times Leader, June 25, 1929.
  - Gossip from California. Los Angeles, undated; 7 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. 1 leaf of holograph notes. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - The Green-Eyed Monster. Los Angeles, undated; 9 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Haydn in England. n.p., undated; 4 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 47)
    With 2 leaves holograph notes.
  - Hollywood--1915--1938. Los Angeles, (?)., 6 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 48)
    With 3 leaves holograph notes.
  - How to Answer the Telephone in Los Angeles. Los Angeles, undated; 2 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Interesting Old Age. n.p., undated; 6 leaves. Typescript with manuscript corrections. (Box 1, Folder 50)
    With note by Majl Ewing (?) on title page.
  - An Italian Physician in Edinburgh. n.p., undated; 8 leaves. Typescript (carbon). (Box 1, Folder 51)
    With another copy.
  - Jonathan and Jonathane. n.p., undated; 4 leaves. Typescript. (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - A 'Knott Garden'. Los Angeles, undated; 7 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Lend Me Your Ears. n.p., undated; 7 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Letter from Hollywood. Los Angeles, undated; 4 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Li'l Dawg Dingoah. Los Angeles, undated; 9 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 56)
    With 2 leaves.holograph notes.
  - Literary Lights of London. n.p., undated; 47 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 57)
    There are 25 numbered leaves and additional pages laid in.
  - Long-Tailed Birds. Los Angeles, undated; 3 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 58)
    With letter of regrets from the New Zealand Herald.
  - The Married Daughter Goes Home for a Visit. Los Angeles, undated; 4 leaves. Signed with the initials A.A.A. on both the title page and at the end of the article. (Box 1, Folder 59)
    With 2 variant copies and 1 leaf of holograph notes.
  - The Ministering Angel Legend. [London], May 8, 1933.; 15 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 60)
    With a mimeograph copy, 8 leaves. An address given to the graduating class of Bishop Johnson College of Nursing at their commencement exercises, St. Paul's Cathedral.
  - Mirandy. Los Angeles, 1938.; 5 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 61)
    With a clipping of the article which appeared in Cornhill Magazine.
  - Missing Act. n.p., 1928.; 3 leaves. Typescript (carbon). Incomplete. (Box 1, Folder 62)
    Part of a manuscript for posthumous publication(?).
  - More Every Day Drama in Los Angeles. n.p., undated; 4 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Mostly about Movie Magnates. Los Angeles, undated; 6 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 64)
    With 1 variant copy, 6 leaves and 1 leaf of holograph notes.
  - Musical Proverbs. Los Angeles, 1939.; 5 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 65)
    With a letter of regrets from The Music Teacher & Piano Student, London, and 2 leaves of holograph notes.
  - My Godson. Los Angeles, undated; 2 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Nightmare. Los Angeles, undated; 3 leaves. Typescript. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Noon News. Los Angeles, undated; 9 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Nos Vacances en France et La Différence Entre le Lycée Français et the American High School. n.p., undated; 10 leaves, 9 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Noted Here and There. n.p., undated; 2 leaves. Typescript. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Odd Size. Los Angeles, undated; 3 leaves. Typescript. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - On a Certain Knack in Asking Questions. n.p., undated; 4 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - On Boners. Los Angeles, undated; 7 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Other People's Treats. n.p., undated; 4 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Our Shadows. Los Angeles, undated; 5 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    With 1 variant copy and 1 leaf holograph notes.
  - Our Thomas Again. n.p., undated; 6 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Overheard at Dresden. Hampstead, undated; 3 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Paris to Nantes in a Month. Los Angeles, undated; 3 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - The Paying Guest, and the Jewed Hostess. Los Angeles, undated; 4 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Plantation Poet. n.p., undated; 2 leaves. Typescript (carbon). (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Points of View. Los Angeles, undated; 3 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections, initialed A.A.A. at the end of the article. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    With another copy and 1 leaf of holograph notes.
  - Pop Goes the Weasel. Los Angeles, undated; 7 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    With a note suggesting another title, The dollar through an Englishwoman's eyes.
  - Practical Room. Los Angeles, undated; 5 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections and 1 leaf of holograph notes. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Precepts for Italian Children, Written in 1547. Los Angeles, undated; 3 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    With another copy and 1 leaf holograph notes.
  - The Psychic Sense. Los Angeles, undated; 6 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - The Psychology of Boredom. n.p., undated; 5 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Pudding Number Three Hundred and Sixty Five. Los Angeles, undated; 6 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Queen Victoria, Prince Albert, and Mrs. Grundy. n.p., undated; 18 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Radiance. n.p., undated; 5 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Reply to Mary Borden. n.p., 1928.; 5 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    This is a response to English Mustard for the American Woman by Mary Borden which appeared in Harper's Magazine, July 14, 1928. 2 clippings are included.
  - Retranchement. n.p., undated; 4 leaves. Holograph. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - The Romance of Black Edward. n.p., undated; 4 leaves. Typescript with corrections. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Savants at Play. n.p., undated; 8 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. Signed at the end of the article. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Scotland - 1894. Los Angeles, undated; 11 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Seen and Heard in Los Angeles. Los Angeles, undated; 4 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Sermon Topics in Los Angeles. Los Angeles, undated; 4 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 30)
    With 1 variant copy and 2 leaves of holograph notes.
  - Seven Against Sylvia. Los Angeles, undated; 5 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Ship Models. n.p., undated; 4 leaves. Typescript. (Box 2, Folder 32)
    With another copy, 3 leaves, typescript (carbon).
  - Sir J.M. Barrie, the Puck of Stageland. n.p., undated; 21 numbered pages, with additional pages laid in. Sewn with cotton cord in the upper left corner. (Box 2, Folder 33)
    With 9 clippings, brochure issued by the Women's Christian Temperance Union, New Zealand, and 2 leaves of holograph notes.
  - The Sirens. Adapted from The Odyssey, by Lady Adams. Los Angeles, undated; 3 leaves. (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Some Stories from the Other Side. Los Angeles, undated; 9 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - S.O.S. from Boarding School. Los Angeles, undated; 4 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Special Formula. Los Angeles, undated; 6 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 37)
    With 2 leaves ephemera and 2 leaves holograph notes.
  - Stand and Stare. Los Angeles, undated; 3 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Standardized America. Los Angeles, undated; 8 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Stopping Off at New Orleans. n.p., undated; 2 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - A Suggestion. Los Angeles, undated; 3 leaves. Typescript. (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - That Knuckle-End of England. Los Angeles, undated; 3 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 42)
    With 1 variant copy, letter of regrets from the New Zealand Herald, and 1 p. holograph notes.
  - That's Not Cricket. Los Angeles, undated; 4 leaves. Typescript. (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - They Asked Us to Dine. Los Angeles, undated; 5 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Things Heard and Seen. Los Angeles, undated; 5 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Things Seen and Heard. n.p., undated; 4 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Thomas. Los Angeles, undated; 1 leaf. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Three Pianos. Los Angeles, undated; 2 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - To Be Continued. Los Angeles, undated; 4 leaves. Typescript. (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Tramps in America. Los Angeles, undated; 4 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Twelve Stories. Los Angeles, undated; 10 leaves. Typescript. (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Two Californian Educationists. Los Angeles, undated; 7 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 52)
    With card from The Auckland Star and 1 leaf of holograph notes.
  - Uncontrolled. Los Angeles, undated; 2 leaves. Typescript. (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Unfinished Dramas in Life. n.p., undated; 3 leaves. Typescript (carbon). (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - An Unrehearsed Ending. Los Angeles, undated; 3 leaves. Typescript. (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - [Untitled]. n.p., undated; 10 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 56)
    With 1 leaf holograph notes. Beginning, Their wedding had been a nine days' wonder...
  - War Souvenirs. n.p., undated; 3 leaves. Typescript. (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - The Waur Game. Somewhere in Scotland. Los Angeles, Late August 1914. undated; 2 leaves. Typescript. (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Weddings While You Wait. Los Angeles, undated; 2 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Which Sir Walter? Los Angeles, undated; 7 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Words Wanted. Los Angeles, undated; 1 leaf. Typescript. (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - The Wordsworths in Scotland. Los Angeles, undated; 6 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Young American Love. Los Angeles, undated; 18 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 63)
    With 4 leaves holograph notes. Sewn with cotton string in upper left corner.
  - The Younger the Richer. Los Angeles, undated; 6 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - [Suggestions for Punch]. n.p., undated; 55 items. Holograph and typescript. (Box 2, Folder 65)
- Notes, Fragments, Clippings, Speeches, Photographs, Ephemera (Box 3)
  - Notes, fragments., 27 items. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Poems for children collected by Lady Adams., 8 items, 4 clippings. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    With a note by Majl Ewing regarding Lady Adams's intention to collect children's poems and set them to music.
  - Untitled speech. n.p., undated; 6 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Beginning, I regret that I am not going to be able to talk to you in French today...
  - Untitled story. n.p., undated; 8 leaves, folded (15pp.). Holograph. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Beginning, People had always said it would happen --...
  - Regarding J.M. Barrie. n.p., undated; 2 leaves. Typescript. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Beginning, You remember the story in 'A Window in Thrums,'...
  - Untitled story. n.p., undated; 4 leaves, folded (10pp.). Holograph. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Beginning, I am condemned to death...
  - Untitled speech. n.p., undated; 3 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Regarding Percy Grainger.
  - Clippings and other ephemera collected by Lady Adams., 7 items. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Includes a menu from the Stanley Hotel, Murree.
  - Articles by and about Lady Adams., 28 clippings and 8 loose pages from a scrapbook. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Photographs., 21 items. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Includes photograph of a portrait of Sir John Adams and several photographs of Lady Adams.
  - Clippings regarding the death of Lady Adams and related material., 5 items. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Includes articles regarding a memorial volume, Tea-Time, composed of Lady Adams's articles compiled by her friends, and a memorial booklet, Lady Adams by W. Bertrand Stevens.
  - Notes by Majl Ewing. ca.(?)., 1942; 4 leaves. Holograph. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Notes for the memorial volume, Tea-Time.
  - Material related to the production of Tea-Time, Los Angeles: Times-Mirror, 1942-1945.; 17 items. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Includes page proofs, a prospectus, typescript and holograph notes, and a copy of the book.
  - Cahier de Daisy Cook, Appartenant à Littérature. [Villa] Richemont, Genève, Swisse, [ca.]., 1885-86; ca. 75pp. Holograph. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Bulletin of the Garden Club of America. vol.48 no.6 ()., November 1960; 2 items. 2 copies. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    With article on Beatrix Farrand on p. 26.
  - Reef Point Gardens Bulletin. Bar-Harbor, Maine. vol.1 no.1-16 ()., August 1946-June 1956; 16 items. (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Correspondence (Box 4)
  - Adams, Agnes Anne (Cook). Letters to Mrs. Spencer (Frances) Thorpe, 1934-1936.; 5 items. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Adams, Agnes Anne (Cook). Invitation for Mr. and Mrs. Spencer Thorpe., undated; 1 item. Printed card with holograph message. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Anderson, Maggie. Letter to Lady Agnes Adams., undated; 1 item. (Incomplete). Torn and mended with packing tape. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Barnett, P.A. and Annie. Letters to John and Agnes Adams., 1915.; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Bliss, Mildred. Letters to Mrs. Spencer Thorpe., 1941-1945.; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Cook, R. Haldane. Letters to Majl Ewing., 1942.; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    With a pencil sketch and photograph enclosed.
  - Cockerell, Theo. D.A. Letters to Lady Adams., 1940.; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Cornhill Magazine, London. Letter to Lady Adams, 1935.; 1 item. Signed Gorell. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Dobbin. Letters to Lady Adams, 1915.; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 9)